guys it says solve for x x squared
equals one so I think I want to use the
logarithms to solve this so let's copy
down the x squared equals one and let's
make some room so we can plug in the
natural log so before we move on we have
to verify that X does not equal zero and
if we check up here 0 is not a solution
to this so we know that X does not equal
zero so now we can move on one of the
properties of logarithms is this
exponent can be brought to the front so
we end up with two natural log of x
equals natural log of one the input of a
natural log must be positive so let's
make this absolute value of x it wasn't
an issue before because it was being
squared but now it's no longer being
squared next let's divide both sides by
two these twos cancel so on the left
hand side we just have the natural log
of x and on the right hand side another
way to rewrite this is one half natural
log of one so just like before when we
brought the two to the front this one
half can become the exponent so the
one-half exponent means the same thing
as the square root so one to the
one-half is the same thing as the square
root of one and let's bring down the
rest of this stuff so natural log of
square root of 1 is just natural log of
1 one and next for both sides of the
equation we're going to do e to the
power of e to the power of a natural log
or inverse operation so the left-hand
side is just going to be absolute value
of x and on the right hand side same
thing so we're just left with one and
now we have the absolute value of x is
equal to one in order for this to be
true the X inside the absolute value
would have to be either one or negative
one and that's the answer to our
question let's put a box around it so if
you ever see x squared is equal to one
we know that X is equal to one or
negative one how exciting